<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rootGuideline>
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>LiSAFE_user_manual</tagGD>
		<nameGD>LiSafe_UserManual.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>User manual for the Li-SAFE portal</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>info_templates</tagGD>
		<nameGD>Info Template training manual battery_ Li-ion 20140801.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>Information on the topics in the rescue and training manual, and the specific colouring.
		This document is a template made by CTIF Commission for Extrication and New Technology in cooperation with RECHARGE. Designer is Kurt Vollmacher (project leader).</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>example_template_training_manual_battery</tagGD>
		<nameGD>Filled in template training manual battery_Li_ion_20140801.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>Example of the template 'Rescue and training manual battery for vehicle', made by CTIF Commission for Extrication and New Technology</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>	
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>guidelines_filling_template_vehicle</tagGD>
		<nameGD>Guidlines Template rescue and training manual vehicle Car 16 08 2014.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>Example of a 'Information for first and second responders rescue and training manual vehicle' sheet, made by CTIF Commission for Extrication and New Technology, Designer Kurt Vollmacher project leader.</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>symbol_rescue_training_manual</tagGD>
		<nameGD>Symbols to be used in the rescue and training manual and rescue sheet 20140625.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>Overview of the symbols used in the rescue and training manual for battery and for the vehicle.</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>standard_overview</tagGD>
		<nameGD>LiSAFE_Standards_overviews.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>This document contains the meshes made in the Battery Safety project to identify the most important test and safety standards for Lithium-ion batteries</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>storage_guidelines</tagGD>
		<nameGD>LiSAFE_Lithium-Ion batteries_storage guidelines.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>Document with guidelines for to store Lithium-ion batteries safely and guidelines on how to handle Lithium-ion batteries on fire</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>	
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>storage_info_sheet</tagGD>
		<nameGD>Information for rescue and emergency services lithium ion batteries in a storage facility.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>Example of a information sheet for rescue and emergency services concerning Lithium-ion batteries in storage facilities. 
		This document is a template made by CTIF Commission for Extrication and New Technology in cooperation with RECHARGE. Designer is Kurt VOllmacher (project leader).</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>
	<guideline>
		<tagGD>release_note_1</tagGD>
		<nameGD>Li-SAFE_REL_1.0_Release_note.pdf</nameGD>
		<descriptionGD>Release note of the release Li-SAFE_Rel_1.0</descriptionGD>
	</guideline>
	
	
 </rootGuideline>