<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rootMaterial xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_001</idMat>
		<nameMat>Coating of polymer/ceramic composite on one (or both) of the electrodes</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>The coating protects the electrodes materials from side reaction</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Increase in the thermal stability of the coated materials in contact with the electrolyte</improveMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_002</idMat>
		<nameMat>AlF3-coating</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<improveMat>Improves the thermal stability of NMC materials by 20°C by reducing the total peak heating rate (and severity) during a runaway reaction</improveMat>
		<refMat>B. Xu, D. Qian, Z. Wang, and Y. S. Meng, “Recent progress in cathode materials research for advanced lithium ion batteries”, Mater. Sci. Eng. R Reports, vol. 73, no. 5–6, pp. 51–65, May 2012.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_003</idMat>
		<nameMat>LiFePO4/PTC composite electrodes</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Self-current-limiting effect at 90°C</effectMat>
		<improveMat>No degradation during cycling
Prevent thermal runaway before the occurrence of side reactions and better protect lithium ion battery during the abnormal temperature increasing</improveMat>
		<refMat>H. Zhong, C. Kong, H. Zhan, C. Zhan, and Y. Zhou, 
“Safe positive temperature coefficient composite cathode for lithium ion battery”, J. Power Sources, vol. 216, pp. 273–280, 2012</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_004</idMat>
		<nameMat>LiCoO2/P3DT (poly(3-dodecylthiophene)</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Self-activating thermal protection for lithium ion batteries</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Improves cycling performance at ambient temperature, but also a thermal shutdown action at an elevated temperature of 110°C</improveMat>
		<refMat>L. Xia, S.-L. Li, X.-P. Ai, H.-X. Yang, and Y.-L. Cao, “Temperature-sensitive cathode materials for safer lithium-ion batteries”, 
Energy Environ. Sci., vol. 4, no. 8, p. 2845, Aug. 2011.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_005</idMat>
		<nameMat>LiMn2O4 coated with poly(diallyldimethylammonium chloride)</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>The PDDA layer blocks surface reactions that cause degradation of the cathode</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Improved thermal stability in an organic electrolyte under charge and discharge</improveMat>
		<refMat>P. G. Balakrishnan, R. Ramesh, and T. Prem Kumar, “Safety mechanisms in lithium-ion batteries”, J. Power Sources, vol. 155, no. 2, pp. 401–414, Apr. 2006.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_006</idMat>
		<nameMat>Multilayered cathode structure</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>The sub layer acts as an ohmic barrier and shuts the charging current down</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Prevent from overcharge</improveMat>
		<refMat>N. Imachi, Y. Takano, H. Fujimoto, Y. Kida, and S. Fujitani, “Layered Cathode for Improving Safety of Li-Ion Batteries”, J. Electrochem. Soc., vol. 154, no. 5, p. A412, 2007.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_007</idMat>
		<nameMat>Separator: laminated layers of polypropylene and polyethylene</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Separator</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Maintain mechanical integrity at least up to 165°C</improveMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_008</idMat>
		<nameMat>Composite separator 
(polymer and ceramic particles (Al2O3 or SiO2) dispersed in the bulk of the polymer)</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Shutdown separator</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Improvement in thermal stability along with improved 
overcharge abuse tolerance under higher voltage test conditions</improveMat>
		<refMat>C. Markets, “The Role of Separators in Lithium-Ion Cell Safety”, Electrochem. Soc. Interface, 2012.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_009</idMat>
		<nameMat>Coating of polymer/ceramic composite on the separator</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Shutdown separator</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Improvement in thermal stability along with improved 
overcharge abuse tolerance under higher voltage test conditions</improveMat>
		<refMat>C. Markets, “The Role of Separators in Lithium-Ion Cell Safety", Electrochem. Soc. Interface, 2012.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_010</idMat>
		<nameMat>Flame retarding separator</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Reduces the flammability of the liquid electrolyte</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Improved thermal stability, higher ionic conductivity and stable cycling performance</improveMat>
		<refMat>J.-J. Woo, S. H. Nam, S.-J. Seo, S.-H. Yun, W. B. Kim, T. Xu, and S.-H. Moon,  “A flame retarding separator with improved thermal stability for safe lithium-ion batteries”, Electrochemistry Communications, vol. 35. pp. 68–71, 2013.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_011</idMat>
		<nameMat>Electroactive polymers</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Ability to switch rapidly between 
conductive and insulating states and sustain high-current densities</effectMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_012</idMat>
		<nameMat>Gel electrolytes</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Flexible framework to host a liquid electrolyte</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Decrease the electrolyte leakage</improveMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_013</idMat>
		<nameMat>Redox shuttle</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Can be reversibly oxidized/reduced at characteristic potential and thus consumes excess charge mechanism</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Internal overcharge protection mechanism</improveMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_014</idMat>
		<nameMat>Inactivation agents</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Lead to reactions forming copious amounts of gas</effectMat>
		<improveMat>The generated gas triggers cell venting leading to
 irreversible inactivation of the individual battery cell and the whole battery pack</improveMat>
		<refMat>D. Lisbona and T. Snee, “A review of hazards associated with primary lithium and lithium-ion batteries”, Process Saf. Environ. Prot., vol. 89, no. 6, pp. 434–442, Nov. 2011.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_015</idMat>
		<nameMat>Flame-retardant additive</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<effectMat>Decrease the flammability of the electrolyte</effectMat>
		<improveMat>Increases the thermal stability of the electrolyte
Suppression of the exothermic heat generation of the electrolyte around 120°C</improveMat>
		<refMat>J. Wen, Y. Yu, and C. Chen, “A Review on Lithium-Ion Batteries Safety Issues: Existing Problems and Possible Solutions”, Mater. Express, vol. 2, no. 3, pp. 197–212, Sep. 2012.</refMat>
	</material>
	<material>
		<idMat>mat_016</idMat>
		<nameMat>Ionic liquid</nameMat>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<proc>Cell design and development</proc>
		<improveMat>Non-flammable, non-volatile, low heat of reaction with active materials, safely operate in a wide temperature range</improveMat>
		<refMat>E. P. Roth and C. J. Orendorff, “How Electrolytes Influence Battery Safety”,
Electrochem. Soc. Interface, 2012.</refMat>
	</material>
</rootMaterial>