<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc></proc>	
<title>Battery Life Cycle</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><h1>Purpose and scope</h1></p>
			<p>This top level overview gives the life cycle for the battery. The life cycle starts with the end of line 
				inspection of the cells and ends with the recycling of the cells. In between the following major processes occur:</p>
			<ul><li>Internal logistics and storage of cells, modules, battery packs</li>
			<li>Transportation of the different components between different production plants</li>
			<li>Assembly of modules and battery packs</li>
			<li>Use of a battery pack in a vehicle</li>
			<li>Recycling battery packs, modules and cells</li>
			<li>Handling and storage of damaged cells, modules and battery packs.</li></ul>
			<p>For every process and step the Li-SAFE portal gives</p>
			<ul><li>information on applicable standards,</li>
			<li>recommendations concerning safety, prevention, storage, good practices, ...</li>
			<li>materials and components which can increase the safety of the battery (cell, module or pack)</li>
			<li>information on the test laboratories which can performed the standardized test.</li></ul>													
			<p><h1>Structure of the process</h1></p>								
			<ul><li><b>Cell level</b>: together with the last phases of the cell production (end of line testing) information about 
			<b>cell design and development</b>is given. This last gives information about materials, components which can make the cell safer.</li>
			<li><b>Module level</b>: this part starts from<b>module assembly</b>in which the cells are used to make a module and 
				ends with the<b>pack assembly processes</b>. design and development instructions are given in<b>Module design and development</b>.</li>
			<li><b>Pack level</b>: this part starts from<b>pack assembly</b>in which the modules are used to make a pack and ends 
				with the<b>vehicle assembly processes</b>. design and development instructions are given in<b>Pack design and development</b></li>
			<li><b>Vehicle level</b>: this is the part of the life cycle in which the battery is contained in a vehicle starting from 
				production and ending at the end of life of the vehicle. design and development instructions are given in<b>Vehicle design and development</b>.</li>
			<li><b>Recycling</b>: this part gives information about recycling packs, modules and cells.</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>		
	</paragraph>
</description>	
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>	
</step>