<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Pack assembly</proc>
<title>Connecting the modules to form a pack</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module</prodType>
		<act>assembling | lifting | placing | moving</act>
		<recoms>recomm_18</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_19</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_27</recoms>			
		<recoms>recomm_28</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_30</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_34</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_37</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_39</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_40</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_41</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_42</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
		<p>In this step the interconnections between the modules are made. During this assembling process, mechanical and electrical abuse shall be avoided</p>
		<p>When more than one modules are connected which each other the voltage, can increase above the 60VDC.
		This means that the risk electrocution exists. To avoid electrocution the current collectors of the modules can be covered.  
		Whenever the operators works on high voltage parts high voltage gloves need to be worn and high voltage tools need to be used.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack | Module</prodType>
		<act>assembling</act>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When all interconnections between the modules are made, the end connectors are placed. These end connectors connect the first and last module
			to cabling of the pack. From this point, a pack is formed. Different systems can be used for this (e.g. bus bar system).
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<act>assembling | lifting | placing | moving</act>
		<recoms>recomm_69</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_70</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_72</recoms>			
		<recoms>recomm_77</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_79</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
		<p>Once the modules are connected to each other, a pack is formed with voltage higher than 60VDC. The main risk whenever a 
		high voltage battery pack is handled is electrocution. In these situations high voltage gloves and high voltage tools are mandatory. 
		Whenever possible, the connectors of the pack need to be covered.</p>
		<p>To avoid the start of a thermal runaway, electrical and mechanical abuse shall always be avoided 
		during the assembling process. The temperature need to be checked on a regular base.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>
