<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Repair packs</proc>	
<title>Repairing packs after pack assembly</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged pack</prodType>
		<act>lifting | moving | placing</act>
		<recoms>recomm_88</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
				<p>When a damaged module can be repaired, precautions to avoid electrocutions need to be taken when the damaged module is lifted, moved, 
				and placed in the repair area. Covering the battery pack connectors is a good measure. (service disconnect ook ???)</p>]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged pack</prodType>
		<act>unpacking</act>
		<recoms>recomm_88</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_90</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
				<p>In the repair area the damaged pack can be unpacked. The operator need to wear high voltage gloves to 
				avoid electrocution. The connectors need to be covered.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged pack</prodType>
		<act>pack disassembling</act>		
		<recoms>recomm_88</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_90</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_92</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_98</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_99</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_100</recoms>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
				<p>After unpacking the damaged pack, the pack can be disassembled. In this step electrocution stays the main risk. Next to the measures 
				to prevent electrocution (high voltage tools and gloves, covering of connectors), precautions to avoid electrical abuse are needed. By 
				avoiding electrical abuse, the temperature increase and possible gas formation cannot occur. 
				The enclosure of the pack needs to be resistant against internal pressure to avoid rupture in case gas formation occurs. 
				The operator needs to wear the appropriate protection equipment (safety glasses and gloves) to decrease the severity of possible injuries 
				due to the rupture of the casing.</p>
		]]></htmltext>	
		
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module</prodType>
		<act>pack disassembling</act>
		<recoms>recomm_43</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_44</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_45</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
				<p>The damaged pack can contain good not damaged modules which needs to be handled 
				during the disassembling of the pack. When modules, which are connected to each other, are handled by 
				an operator the risk on electrocution exist (voltage is higher than 60V DC). To avoid the electrocution the 
				module connector need to be covered as soon as possible. The operator needs to use high voltage gloves and glasses.</p>]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged module</prodType>
		<act>packing</act>
		<recoms>recomm_53</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_56</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_64</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_65</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The damaged pack can contain damaged modules. After the disassembling of the damaged pack, the damaged modules 
				need to be removed from the pack repair area.  Before they can be removed, the damaged modules need to be packed. 
				During the packing of the module external short circuit need to be avoided. This can be done by covering the module connector. 
				The operator needs to wear safety gloves and glasses.</p>
			<p>To avoid thermal runaway the temperature needs to be checked regualary. To avoid propagation, moulded trays can be used to separate modules where needed.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged module</prodType>
		<act>lifting | moving | placing</act>
		<recoms>recomm_46</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_47</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_53</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_56</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_57</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_64</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_65</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the damaged modules are removed from the pack repairs area, precautions need to be taken when the damaged module is moved, lifted and placed. The following recommendations are valid for the package:</p>
			<ul><li>Appropriate package for the damaged module to avoid external short circuit</li>
			<li>Individual damaged modules shall be separated by moulded trays to avoid thermal runaway propagation</li>
			<li>The enclosure shall be resistant against mechanical abuse which could lead to gas formation</li>
			<li>To avoid injuries due to rupture of a module the enclosure needs to be resistant against internal pressure.</li></ul>
			<p>To further decrease the risk and the severity of injuries caused by external short circuit, one current connector needs to be covered and the operator needs to wear safety glasses and gloves.</p>
			<p>During these activities the temperature shall be monitored to detect the start of a thermal runaway.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>assembling</act>
		<recoms>recomm_40</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_41</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_42</recoms>		
		<recoms>recomm_69</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_70</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_72</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>After the disassembling of the pack and removing the damaged components, the pack can be reassembled again. When the modules are connected, the risk of electrocution increases. To avoid the electrocution the module connector need to be covered as soon as possible. The operator needs to use high voltage gloves and glasses. The correct high voltage tools are mandatory.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<act>measuring | moving</act>		
		<recoms>recomm_69</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_72</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the pack is reassembled the pack can be moved and measured by the operator. It is recommended to cover the connectors whenever it is possible. The operator shall wear the high voltage gloves during these activities.</p>
			<p>The pack can be moved to the production line. The connectors need to be covered during these activities.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>	
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>
