<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Pack design and development</proc>	
<title>Design and Requirements</title>	
<description>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2929</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>4.12</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong>Fault analysis</strong></p>
			<p>The fault analysis validates that plausible single point faults will not results in fire, explosion, enclosure rupture or high voltage hazard. The following partial list of fault conditions shall be included in the analysis. Additional fault conditions, appropriate to the battery system design, shall also be included as determined by the responsible organization.</p>
			<ul><li>Battery cell internal failures (e.g., internal short)</li>
			<li>Failures in the charge control system</li>
			<li>Failures in the discharge control system</li>
			<li>Failures in the temperature control system</li></ul>
			<p>The output of the analysis is a completed and documented fault analysis, including closure of all identified action items, showing that plausible single point faults will not result in fire, explosion, battery enclosure rupture or high voltage hazard.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.7</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong>Quality plan</strong></p>
			<p>The manufacturer shall prepare and implement a quality plan that defines procedures for the inspection of materials, components, cells and which covers the whole process of producing each type of cell. Manufacturers should understand their process capabilities and should institute the necessary process controls as they relate to product safety.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<components>comp_001</components>
		<components>comp_004</components>
		<components>comp_005</components>
		<components>comp_006</components>
		<components>comp_007</components>
		<components>comp_008</components>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong>Safety components</strong></p>
			<p>To ensure the design and development of a safe battery pack, we must ensure all levels of battery manufacturing: cell, module, pack, system, user and environment. The aim of this step is to give pack assemblers more background information on the components used in a pack to make it safer (less reactive, more stable).</p>
			<p>Packs under electrical, mechanical or thermal abuse can go into thermal runaway. To prevent these types of abuses or to reduce their risks, the following components can be added to the pack design:</p>
			<ul><li><b>Current interrupt device:</b> in-built device to prevent overcharge which can lead to gas formation and thermal runaway</li>
			<li><b>Thermal fuse:</b> a wire of a fusible alloy with resistance and thermal characteristics that allow it to melt when a pre-set current flows through it. Thermal fuses are employed as protection against thermal runaway and are usually set to open at 30–50°C above the maximum operating temperature of the battery.</li></ul>
			<p>It is also common to add electronics to the pack which monitor the packs state and with management systems which react (ex open the battery circuit) when a wrongful condition is detected (ex. short circuit) to prevent damages to the pack. The following electronics are used.<p>
			<ul><li><b>Thermistors:</b> sense the internal temperature of the battery, and provide information to an external control through a calibrated resistance</li>
			<li><b>Protection circuit module (PCM):</b> the PCM opens the battery circuit to prevent damage to the module</li>
			<li><b>Battery management system (BMS):</b> BMS notifies the user of an error and execute the preset correction procedure.</li></ul>
			<p>To prevent temperature increase and thus thermal runaway, a cooling system is added to dissipate the excess of heat when the temperature rises exceed a certain limit. </p>		
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext>
				<![CDATA[<p><strong>Design requirements</strong></p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong><i>Materials</i></strong></p>
			<p>For the selection of the material the following consideration need to be taken into consideration:</p>
			<ul><li>Resistance to impact</li>
			<li>Crush resistance</li>
			<li>Abnormal operations</li>
			<li>Severe conditions</li>
			<li>Mold-stress relief distortion. This addresses also the dimensional stability for polymeric materials.</li></ul>
			<p>When a non-metal (polymeric) material is used, the factors needs to be considered with respect to thermal aging. These materials shall be suitable for the temperature range. The UV resistance for materials exposed to sunlight can be tested according to specific standards. Materials employed as electrical insulation in the assembly shall be resistant to deterioration that would result in an electrical shock or other safety hazard. Gaskets and seals relied upon for safety shall be determined suitable for the temperatures they are exposed to and other conditions of use.</p>
			<p>For metallic pack enclosures corrosion resistant is necessary. This can be obtained with suitable plating or coating processes. The metallic pack enclosure may be provided with an insulating liner to prevent shorting of battery conductors. The used insulating liner shall consist of non-moisture absorbent materials that have a temperature rating suitable for temperatures within the enclosure during operation of the pack. The conductive parts in contact at terminals and connections shall not be subject to corrosion due to electrochemical action.</p>						
			]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong><i>Enclosures</i></strong></p>
			<p>The enclosure openings shall be designed to prevent inadvertent access to hazardous parts as installed in the vehicle. The enclosure needs to prevent inadvertent access to the high voltage circuits during servicing and handling. When vents are placed on the enclosure, the shall be located in such way that dispersion of gases or toxic materials in the passenger compartment is prevented. The assembly shall comply with its IP rating o fluids and other foreign materials.</p>
			]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong><i>Wiring and terminals</i></strong></p>
			<p>Internal wiring and its insulation shall be sufficient to withstand the maximum anticipated current, voltage and temperature requirements . The orientation of wiring shall be such that adequate clearances and creepage distances are maintained between connectors. The mechanical integrity of internal connections shall be sufficient to accommodate conditions of reasonably foreseeable misuse.</p>
			]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.6</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>High voltage wiring shall be readily distinguishable from the low voltage wiring harnesses by using orange colored insulation or wiring harness jacketing or covers. Internal wiring of high voltage circuits shall also be colored primarily orange or enclosed in junction boxes with high voltage warning labels.</p>
			<p>Rounded bushings should be used on those places where insulated wires pass trough a metal wall. If bushings aren’t used, the surfaces need to be smooth, free of burrs, fins, sharp edges. This is needed to prevent abrasion of the insulation.</p>
			]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
			<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
			<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.5.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
			<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.5.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The design of the terminals shall ensure that maximum anticipated current can be carried. Conductive materials with good mechanical strength and corrosion resistance shall be used for external terminal contact surfaces. The way they are arranged shall minimize the risk of short circuit . External terminals shall be designed to prevent inadvertent shorting, inadvertent misalignment or disconnections.  </p>
			<p>Uninsulated live parts (including terminals) shall be secured to prevent turning, shifting, reducing electrical spacing or creating a short circuit.</p>
			<p><strong><i>Spacing and separation of circuits</i></strong></p>
			<p>To prevent short circuits electrical circuits within the pack at opposite polarity shall be provided with reliable physical spacing. For the minimum over surface and through air spacings for the electrical spacings in circuit are defined in the standards (e.g. UL 2580) . An insulated conductor shall be reliably retained so that it cannot contact an uninsulated live part of a circuit operating at a different voltage.</p>]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J1797</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<htmltext>
				<![CDATA[<p><strong>Mechanical requirements</strong></p>]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J1797</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J1797</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J1797</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Mechanical retention system to attach components should provide for retention in the three mutually perpendicular axes. To restrain both single modules and multiple modules connected together in a system, multitude methods can be used. Note that the electrical cables and connections are not part of an acceptable retention system. A couple of attention point shall be taken into account:</p>
			<ul><li>The strength over time and corrosion should be considered when the fasteners are selected and</li>
			<li>The clamping force shall not damage the structures and systems.</li>
			<li>Any retention system should maintain electrical isolation during a crash.</li>
			<li>The retention system should prevent current leakage and should be protected against electrolyte corrosion.</li>
			<li>If an air draft system is used for thermal management or hydrogen gas emissions, the retention system should not hinder air flow around the module(s) needed for proper thermal management or venting of the entire battery system.</li>
			<li>The retention system should not interfere with the vent system or high-voltage wiring.</li></ul> 
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J1797</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Battery pack design should consider installation and removal by service personnel. One consideration is structural support of the battery tray during installation and removal after it has been disconnected from the vehicle . During this time, some additional structure (pallet or other) may be needed to support the battery pack to preclude damage and enable movement by fork lift trucks or cranes to move a battery pack from the service bay to a transport truck in instances of swapping or offsite servicing of a battery pack.</p>	
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.6</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.4.7</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>During the design of the pack durability aspect shall be taken into account. The pack needs to be able to withstand the following physical effects:</p>
			<ul><li>Mechanical shock</li>
			<li>Vibration</li>
			<li>Corrosion</li>
			<li>Abrasion/road hazards</li>
			<li>Exposure to water and other chemical fluids</li>
			<li>Sand and dust</li>
			<li>UV exposure</li></ul> 
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.8</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.8.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>1</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext>
				<![CDATA[<p><strong>Electrical requirements</strong></p>]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>			
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>For each operational mode of the vehicle and associated electrical mode defined . During the ‘Key-on’ mode the battery can be discharged. In normal operations.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.2</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.2.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.2</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.2.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.2</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.2.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Performance ratings of a battery pack system are established by the vehicle manufacturer and the support of subsystem or component manufacturer for measuring net performance ratings of individual components and the system . For the different types of wiring and connectors the following applies:</p>
			<ul><li>Traction wiring within a battery pack system is high current, high voltage wiring and interconnects between battery modules. It also includes wiring to a battery pack connector for attachment to the vehicles’ high voltage wiring system.</li>
			<li>Sensor wiring within a battery pack system should be in separate wire harnesses according to voltage range. High voltage sensor leads should be bundled separately and routed apart from low voltage wiring harnesses.</li>
			<li>Utility wiring connectors between the battery pack and the rest of the vehicle should consider separating high and low voltage signals into different connectors with appropriate voltage range markings.</li>
			<li>Contactors or disconnects are recommended to switch the battery circuit. They should de-energize exposed external terminals. They should be located close to or be part of a battery pack. Contactors or disconnects may be packaged external to battery pack systems. In this case, some means should be taken to de-energize exposed terminals or wires. The manufacturer may provide an interlock mechanism that disconnects the battery circuit when the battery is disconnected from the vehicle or the battery tray is opened to allow service.</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.8</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.8.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>A manual disconnect for servicing or access in the event of vehicle collision shall be provided. The following criteria shall be followed for this disconnect</p>
			<ul><li>disconnects both poles of the high voltage circuit(s)</li>
			<li>located in a manner to disconnect the electric energy storage assembly circuit in half or located as close as possible to the positive and negative output terminal</li>
			<li>manual action to break the electrical connection is needed</li>
			<li>does not create exposed conductors capable of becoming energized while exposed and is insulated to prevent shock hazard during actuation</li>
			<li>Capable of disconnecting high voltage circuit under full load conditions at least one time;</li>
			<li>Able to be accessible and to be operated without the use of a tool or other special protective equipment (i.e. flash protection) in the event of a collision</li></ul>
			<p>Note: If an automatic disconnect, located near the pack terminals, is used it may not be reset automatically, it must be capable of handling full load disconnects and shall not result in a hazardous condition upon automatic actuation.</p> to battery pack systems. In this case, some means should be taken to de-energize exposed terminals or wires. The manufacturer may provide an interlock mechanism that disconnects the battery circuit when the battery is disconnected from the vehicle or the battery tray is opened to allow service.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Both battery and vehicle manufacturer  should agree upon the type of fastener that is used to connect the high power leads to the terminal. Vibration, creep, thermal environment, number of times fastener removed and reinstalled, should be considered in system design. The connector used to mate with the terminal land area and cable or bussbar shall be adequate to carry maximum expected current without heat generation that would cause damage to battery modules or interconnects. Terminal torque affects current carrying capability, and is affected by vibration and creep.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>During the design the standards for meeting applicable and useful EMC and transient emissions and susceptibility performance.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.5.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Electrical isolation  of the battery pack both external and internal to the pack should be provided regardless of operating mode including exceptional circumstances.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>1</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The measurement of the isolation resistance of the battery pack shall include auxiliary components located inside the pack housing, e.g. monitoring or temperature-conditioning devices and liquid fluids (if any). The terminals of the pack have generally different isolation resistances against the electric chassis. For safety reasons, the lower one is regarded as the relevant pack isolation resistance. Standards give values for this resistance  and/or procedure to measure this isolation resistance.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.6.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.6.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.6.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.6.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>UL 2580</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5.6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.6.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>High voltage circuits shall be insulated from accessible conductive parts and circuits. Low voltage circuits that are insulated from accessible conductive parts through functional insulation only are considers accessible. The insulation can be achieved by (1) a basic insulation and provided with a protective grounding system for protection in the event of a fault of the basic insulation or by (2) a  system of double or reinforced insulation or by a combination of both.  Parts of the protective grounding system shall be reliably secured in and provided with good metal-to-metal contact. The main ground terminal of the protective ground system shall be identified. The following markings can be used:</p>
			<ul><li>green-colored, not readily removable terminal screw with a hexagonal head;</li>
			<li>green-colored, hexagonal, not readily removable terminal nut;</li>
			<li>green colored pressure wire connector</li>
			<li>word “Ground” or the letters “G”or “GR” or the grounding symbol (IEC 60417, No. 5019)</li>
			<li>otherwise identified by a distinctive green color.</li></ul>
			<p>Conductors, relied upon for the protective grounding and bonding system, shall be sized to handle intended fault currents and if insulated, the insulation shall be green or green and yellow striped in color.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Internal wiring and its insulation shall be sufficient to withstand the maximum anticipated current, voltage and temperature requirements. The orientation of wiring shall be such that adequate clearances and creepage distances are maintained between connectors. The mechanical integrity of internal connections shall be sufficient to accommodate conditions of reasonably foreseeable misuse.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.3.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.3.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.3.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.3.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.6.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.6.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.6.2</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.6.2.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.6.2</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.6.2.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.7.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.7.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.8</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.9</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Persons need to be protected against electric shock. This protection shall be composed of a basic protection measures against direct contact with live parts and measures for protection under single-failure conditions. The protection measures against direct contact shall be provided by either one or both of the following:</p>
			<ul><li><b>Basic insulation of the live parts:</b> the live parts of the electric system are totally encapsulated by insulation that can be removed only by destruction. The insulating material shall be suitable to the maximum working voltage and temperature ratings of the vehicle and its systems.</li>
			<li><b>Barriers/enclosures, preventing access to the live parts:</b>the Iive parts are placed inside enclosures or behind barriers, preventing access to the live parts from any usual direction of access. The barriers/enclosures shall provide sufficient mechanical resistance under normal operating conditions, as specified by the manufacturer. If barriers/enclosures are accessible directly, they shall be opened or removed only by use of tools or maintenance keys or they shall have means to deactivate live parts with class B voltage, e.g. an interlock.</li></ul>
			<p>For protection under single failure conditions the following measures can be used:</p>
			<ul><li>potential equalization</li>
			<li>isolation resistance</li>
			<li>capacitive couplings</li>
			<li>de-energization</li></ul> 
			<p>To test the protection measures against electric shock, standards give specific procedure (see ‘Tests’).</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62133</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Internal wiring and its insulation shall be sufficient to withstand the maximum anticipated current, voltage and temperature requirements. The orientation of wiring shall be such that adequate clearances and creepage distances are maintained between connectors. The mechanical integrity of internal connections shall be sufficient to accommodate conditions of reasonably foreseeable misuse.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>1</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>8</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>8.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>In case of a crash, the electric power system shall be protected against the effects of a short-circuit.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>1</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>If the battery pack is not short-circuit proof in itself, an over-current interruption device shall open the pack circuit  under conditions specified by the vehicle and/or RESS manufacturer, to prevent dangerous effects for persons, the vehicle and the environment.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>1</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Environmental requirements</strong></p>]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The first environmental requirement is the temperature range to which the pack is exposed in the electric vehicle.  Thermal design approaches should consider EV systems temperature performance ranges. A good measure for temperature range in an EV should be –40 °C to 60 °C with a relative humidity range of 10% to 80% at 38 °C.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.2</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.2.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.2.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.2.1.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.2.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.2.1.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>1</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>1</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The second are the  requirement for to handle hazardous physical emissions . Under normal operation (shipping and handling, road hazards, storage and normal driving) no electrolyte leakage from or within the battery pack system should occur. A concern is electrolyte leakage causing ionic conductance in a high voltage system, which, without the proper safety circuits, may energize the vehicle chassis. Performance testing and actual leakage allowed at crash situations should be tested and evaluated according to the specific standards. The possibility on leakage has effect on the clearance and creepage distance and clearance between the connection terminals of the pack.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.1.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3.1</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.1.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The third are the  requirement for to handle gaseous emissions. The gas emissions may fall into either of two categories of toxic and flammable gasses. The gas emission from batteries should be considered in the battery pack design. Two possible provisions are a flash/flame arrestor system in the module and a venting system in the battery pack.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>					
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The last requirement is that the pack shall withstand exposure to altitudes.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.7.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.7.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.7.3</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs><!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2289</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.7.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong>Diagnostics</strong></p>
			<p>The battery system can contain diagnostic devices. The following diagnostics and warnings can be implemented:</p>
			<ul><li>End of line manufacturing diagnostics</li>
			<li>Key-on startup diagnostics and warning</li> 
			<li>Key-on running diagnostics and warning</li>
			<li>Service diagnostics</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>	
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>
