<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Repair vehicle</proc>	
<title>Repairing vehicle after production</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged vehicle</prodType>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the battery pack or its electronics aren't working correctly or are damaged after commisioning, the vehicel needs to go to 
			the repair area where the pack can be removed and replaced by a good one or were the electronics or wiring can replaces. </p>]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged vehicle</prodType>
		<act>driving</act>	
		<recoms>recomm_85</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_114</recoms>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>If it is still possible to drive with the vehicle, the driver needs to adapt its driving style for two reasons</p>
			<ul><li>To be able to anticipate on unexpected situations caused by the damaged pack</li>
			<li>To alert other road users</li></ul>
			<p>Information on where the electrical vehicles are used can be added to the internal transportation plan. Signalisation can be placed to warn other road users.</p>
		]]>	</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged vehicle</prodType>
		<act>towing</act>
		<recoms>recomm_85</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>If it is not possible to drive the vehicle, the vehicle needs to be towed to the repair area. 
			Towing should be done according to the towing instruction. If needed the connectors can be covered to avoid electrocution</p>]]>
		</htmltext>				
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged pack | Damaged vehicle</prodType>
		<act>vehicle disassembling</act>
		<recoms>recomm_101</recoms>	
		<recoms>recomm_102</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_103</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the damaged pack need to be removed from the vehicle the appropriate procedure need to be followed to avoid short circuit
			and electrocution. Good way of working are to remove the server disconnect, cover the end connections and use appropriat protection measures and 
			tooling. when the damaged pack is removed, it must go via internal logistics to a storage and it can be send back to recycler or pack prodcuer. 
			</p>]]>
		</htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack | Vehicle</prodType>
		<act>assembling</act>
		<recoms>recomm_78</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_79</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>A new battery pack can be mounted in the vehicle. During the placing of the pack, mechanical and electrical abuses need to be avoided. This abuse can lead to a thermal runaway in a later phase of the battery pack life cycle.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>	
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>