<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Using EV/HEV</proc>	
<title>Using the electric or hybrid vehicle</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<act>driving</act>
		<recoms>recomm_84</recoms>
		<inputs>vehicle_user_manual</inputs>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Driving</b></p>
			<p>During the use of the vehicle the driver shall know that other road users aren't used to electrical vehicles yet. 
			Due to the lack of engine noise pedestrians won't hear the vehicle coming and they can be surprised that there is a vehicle.
			When driving an EV/HEV the driver needs to be aware of this danger and anticipate on it.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<act>working on the car</act>
		<recoms>recomm_67</recoms>
		<inputs>vehicle_user_manual</inputs>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Maintenance</b></p>
			<p>All maintenance shall be done by skilled personnel who know how to check and repair vehicles with high voltage components. 
			The customer shall be discouraged to work close to the battery pack and other high voltage components.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<act>working on the car</act>
		<inputs>first_responder_guide</inputs>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Towing</b></p>
			<p>It is possible that due to a failure the vehicle needs to be towed. Information on how to tow the vehicle shall be given 
			to the towing and maintenance personnel (second responders) through the ‘Information for first and second responders – rescue 
			and training manual’ of the vehicle. Towing information shall also be available in the user manual.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<inputs>first_responder_guide</inputs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Accident with a (H)EV</b></p>
			<p>First responders (fire brigade, police, medical personnel) can be called for an accident with a hybrid or electric vehicle. They 
			should be informed upfront on the risks and how to safely help the passengers of the vehicle. It is therefore needed that the 
			'Information for first and second responders – rescue and training manual’ of the each vehicle is available for these organizations.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<act>storing</act>
		<recoms>recomm_129</recoms>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Storing (H)EV after an accident</b></p>
			<p>When an accident happens with the (H)EV, the vehicle should be stored outside. A situation is known in which
			a battery pack of crashed vehicle caught fire a couple of days after the crash. By storing the vehicle outside
			damage to the garage or other buildings is avoided. After the crash, an evaluation of the (history) of the car is needed. 
			Input from the pack producer is necessary to evaluate all the risks and effects of the crash. If evaluation shows that 
			it is safe to remove the pack out of the vehicle this can be done. Information about how to handle these situations 
			should be given in the “Battery training manual”.</p>
			<p>Information on what to do in case of an accident can be added to the user manual of the vehicle.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>