<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Vehicle design and development</proc>	
<title>Documentation</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2344</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>5</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>5</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>2</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>3</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>10</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>10</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Owner's manual</b></p>
			<p>The vehicle user should provide an Owner’s Guide or Manual that addresses the unique operating, charging and safety characteristics of the vehicle.  Special attention should be given to the electric safety .</p>
			<p>The following items are recommended to be included:</p>
			<ul><li>Procedures for safe vehicle operation, including operating environments.</li>
			<li>Precautions related to the fluids and materials stored, used, or processed in the vehicle.</li>
			<li>Possible safety hazards posed by vehicle or system operation and appropriate action(s) if a problem is detected.</li>
			<li> Any restrictions or building requirements related to operation, parking or storage in residential garages or commercial structures, and any special requirements for shipping should be noted.</li>
			<li>Charging procedures and safety precautions.</li>
			<li>Precautions related to operator replacement of parts or fluids.</li>
			<li>Information for roadside emergencies.</li>
			<li>Operator service procedures, checks, and maintenance schedules</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>	
		<workproducts>first_response_guide</workproducts>
	</paragraph>		
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2344</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>ISO 6469</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>2</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>9</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>9</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Emergency response guide</b></p>
			<p>Information shall be available for the safety personnel and/or emergency responders with regard to dealing with accidents involving these vehicles.</p>
			<p>The following items are recommended to be included:</p>
			<ul><li>Explanation of hazards associated with the fluids, hazardous voltage systems, and any materials or components in the high voltage system or vehicle in general.</li>
			<li>Identification of vehicle.</li>
			<li>Procedure for verifying that automatic fuel shut-off and electrical disconnection functions have occurred.</li>
			<li>Location and procedures for manual shut-off of fuels and disconnection of electrical bus, if applicable.</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>	
		<workproducts>first_responder_guide</workproducts>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>SAE J2344</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>Server manual</b></p>
			<p>The vehicle manufacturer should be responsible to give information related to vehicle service and maintenance.</p>
			<p>The following items are recommended to address:</p>
			<ul><li>Chemical and physical properties of hazardous materials stored or processed in the vehicle.</li>
			<li>Possible safety hazards posed by the vehicle or its systems during maintenance and appropriate action(s) if a fault is detected.</li>
			<li>First aid procedures specific to the unique hazards of the vehicle.</li>
			<li>Maintenance tools, equipment, and personal protective equipment (PPE).</li>
			<li>Methods and procedures for specific operations (such as charging).</li>
			<li>Suggested and required maintenance items and their schedules.</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>	
	</paragraph>
</description>	
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>