<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Recycling</proc>	
<title>Dismantling the pack at the recycle plant</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<act>lifting | moving | placing</act>
		<recoms>recomm_74</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_75</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_76</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the packs are moved to the recycling line measures need to be taken to avoid leakage, electrocution and thermal runaway. These are respectively:</p>
			<ul><li>Covering the connectors of the battery pack</li>
			<li>Using a enclosure which is resistant against mechanical abuse</li>
			<li>Checking the temperature of the pack on a regular base</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>		
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<act>unpacking</act>
		<recoms>recomm_76</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>During the unpacking of the pack, the temperature needs to be controlled to see if no thermal runaway is started.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>		
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack</prodType>
		<act>pack disassembling</act>
		<recoms>recomm_68</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_71</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_76</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>After unpacking the pack can be disassembled. The main risk here is the electrocution risk. The operator needs to use high voltage tools and high voltage gloves to execute this task.</p> 
			<p>During the disassembling of the pack, the temperature needs to be controlled to see if no thermal runaway is started.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>		
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module</prodType>
		<act>pack disassembling</act>
		<recoms>recomm_43</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_44</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_45</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_20</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When modules, which are connected to each other, are handled by an operator the risk on electrocution exist (voltage is higher than 60V DC). 
			To avoid the electrocution the module connector need to be covered as soon as possible. The operator needs to use high voltage gloves and glasses. 
			When the modules are handled separately, the risk of electrocution disappears but the risk on external short circuit stays. To avoid this short 
			circuit the connector of the module need to stay covered.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>