<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Transportation</proc>	
<title>Preparation for air transport</title>	
<description>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Damaged cell | Module | Damaged module | Pack | Damaged pack</prodType>
		<act>packing</act>
		<workproducts>IATA_DGR</workproducts>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing | labelling</act>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[	
			<p><b><i>Note 1: The legislation and regulation of transporting Lithium-ion batteries by plane is changing rapidly.
			It is therefore recommended that when it is planned to tranport components by plane, the latest regulations
			are verified.</i></b></p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing | labelling</act>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62281</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7.3</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.3.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Regulations concerning air transport of lithium batteries are specified in the Technical Instructions for the Safe 
			Transport of Dangerous Goods by Air published by the International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO) 
			and in the Dangerous Goods Regulations published by the International Air Transport Association (IATA).</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing | labelling</act>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Translational period</strong></h3>
			<p>Depending in the period of production, cells, modules and packs can be transported according to the following time frame:</p>
			<ul><li>Lithium cells, modules and packs manufactured before 1 January 2014 conforming to a design type tested according to the requirements of the 5th revision of the UN Manual of Tests and Criteria, Part III may continue to be transported.</li></ul>
			<h3><strong>Exemptions from the testing requirelments:</strong></h3>
			<p>For exemptions under the air transport mode, see special provision A88.</p>
			<p>The testing requirements in sub-section 38.3 of the Manual of Tests and Criteria do not apply to:</p>
			<ul><li>Low production runs. This consists of not more that 100 cells, modules or packs per year.</li>
			<li>Transport must be approved by the appropriate authority of the State of origin, even if all requirements are met</li></ul>
	]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing</act>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Packaging</strong></h3>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing</act>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62281</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.1</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62281</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>4</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>4.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The packaging needs to avoid mechanical damage during transport, handling and stacking of the goods. This is to avoid crushing of the cells 
			and batteries (which can lead to leakage, venting, rupture, explosion and fire) , unintentional electrical short circuit and corrosion of the terminals.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing</act>
		<recoms>recomm_83</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><b>TO DO add recomm for cell and modules</b></p>
			<p>To avoid propagation of a thermal runaway the following measures can be taken:</p>
			<ul><li> Place cells, modules and damaged cells, damaged modules in moulted trays before they are packed, can avoid propagation of a thermal runaway</li>
			<li>Place battery packs in separated packages and use fire resistant material for these packages</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing</act>	
		<htmltext><![CDATA[	
			<p>Packagings  shall be constructed and closed so as to prevent any loss of contents when prepared for transport which might be cased under normal conditions of transport, by vibrations, or by changes in temperature, humidity or pressure.</p>
			<p>No dangerous residue shall adhere to the outside of packagings during carriage.</p>
			<p>“Overpack’ means an enclosure used (by a single consignor in the case of Class 7)) to contain one or more packages, consolidated into a single unit easier to handle and stow during carriage;</p>
			<p>Examples of Overpack:</p>
			<ul><li>A loading tray such as a pallet, in which several packages are placed or stacked and secured by a plastics strip, shrink or stretch wrapping or other appropriate means</li>
			<li>An outer protective packaging such as a box or a crate</li></ul>
			<p>“Package’ means the complete product of the packaging operation, consisting of the packaging and its contents prepared for dispatch.</p>
			<p>Dangerous goods shall not be packed together in the same outer packaging or in larger packagings, with dangerous or other goods if they react dangerously with each other and cause:</p>
			<ul><li>Combustion or evolution of considerable heat</li>
			<li>Evolution of flammable, asphyciant, oxidizing or toxic gasses</li>
			<li>The formation of corrosive substances</li>
			<li>The formation of unstable substances</li></ul>
			<p>Before being filed and handed over for carriage, every packaging, including IBCs and large packagings, shell be checked to be free from corrosion, contamination or other defects.</p>
			<p>Any packaging which shows signs of weakening, with reference to the approved prototype shall no loner be used or shall be refurbished so that it can pass the tests required for the prototype.</p>
			<p><i>Plastic packagings</i></p>
			<p>For plastics drums and jerricans, rigid plastics IBCs and composite IBCs with plastics inner receptacles, unless otherwise approved by the competent authority, the period of use permitted for carriage of dangerous substances shall be five years from the date of manufacture of the receptacles except where a shorter period of use is prescribed because of the nature of the substance to be carried.</p>
			<p><i>Approved packagings</i></p>
			<p>The packs can be used must have passed specific tests and testing conform to the prototype tested. </p>
			<p>Packagings shall be manufactured, reconditioned and tested under a quality assurance programme which satisfies the competent authority.</p>
			<p>Packagings shall bear markings which are durable, legible and readily visible, constituted by a sequence of symbols, letters and numbers, i.e.:</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure1.jpg" style="height:358px; width:500px" /></p>
			<p>Table with packing codes</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-table1.jpg" style="height:466px; width:700px" /></p>
			<p>„Drums “ mean a flat-ended or convex-ended culindrical packaging made out of metal, fibreboardn plasticsn plywood or other suitable material. This definition also includes packagings of other shapes, e.g. round, taper-necked packagings or pail-shaped packagings. Woorden barrels and erricans are not covered by this definition.</p>
			<p>“Jerrican ” means a metal or plastic packaging of rectangular or polygonal cross-section with one or more orifices.</p>
			<p>“Box ” means a packaging with complete rectangular or polygonal faces, made of metal, word , plywood, reconstituted wood, fiberboard, plastics or other suitable material. Small holes for purposes of ease of handling or opening or to meet classification requirements, are permitted as long as they do not compromise the integrity of the packaging during carriage.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>labelling</act>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Marking</strong></h3>
			<p>The marking of primary lithium cells and batteries should comply with IEC 60086-4. The marking of secondary (rechargeable) lithium cells and batteries should comply with IEC 61960.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>labelling</act>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62281</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>9</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>9.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>On the package the following shall be placed:</p>
			<ul><li>Information that the package contains lithium cells or batteries</li>
			<li>Information to handle the package with care</li>
			<li>Information that in case of damages, it shall be quarantined, inspected and repacked</li>
			<li>Telephone number for more information</li></ul>
			<p>The above information shall be placed in either the shipper’s declaration, or a label attached to existing documents accompanying each shipment.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>labelling</act>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p><strong>UN marking</strong></p>	
			<p>The UN number preceded by the letters “UN” shall be clearly and durably marked on each package.</p>
			<p>Dimensions of the mark:</p>
			<ul><li>The UN number and letters “UN” shall be at least 12 mm high</li>
			<li>For packages of 30 liters capacity or less or of 30 kg maximum net mass, they shall be at least 6 mm in height and except for packages of 5 liter or 5 kg or less when they shell be of an appropriate size.</li></ul>
			<p>Unpackaged article: The marking shall be displayed on the article, on its cradle or on its handling, storage or launching device.</p>
			<p>Marking shall be readily visible and legible and shall be able to withstand open weather exposure without a substantial reduction in effectiveness.</p>
				<p><strong>Label Class 9</strong></p>	
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure2.jpg"/></p>
			<p><strong>Markings used for IATA</strong></p>	
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure8.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Minimum dimensions 120 x 110 mm. Where the packages are of dimensions such that they can only bear smaller labels the label dimensions may be 74 mm x 105 mm.</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure9.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Minimum dimensions 120 x 110 mm</p>
			<p>Example of fully regulated shipment</p>
			
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure10.jpg" style="height:343px; width:700px" /></p>
			<p>Example of small partially exempted shipment</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure11.jpg" style="height:343px; width:700px" /></p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>IATA – Lithium batteries in checked baggage and carry-on baggage</strong></h3>	
			<p><strong>Goods acceptable without the Operator’s approval</strong></p>
			<p>Portable electronic devices (such as watches, calculating machines, cameras, cellular phones, map-top computers, camcorders)</p>
			<p>Spare batteries must be individually protected to prevent short circuits and carried in carry-on baggage only.</p>
			<p>In addition, lithium batteries are subjected to the following conditions:</p>
			<ul><li>Each installed or spare battery must not exceed (for lithium ion batteries) a watt-hour rating of not more than 100 Wh.</li>
			<li>Batteries and cells must be of a type that meets the requirements of the UN Manual of Tests and Criteria, Part III, subsection 38.3.</li>
			<li>If devices are carried in checked baggage the passenger must take measures to prevent unintentional activation.</li></ul>

			<p><strong>Goods acceptable with operator approval as carry-on baggage only</strong></p>
			<p>Lithium ion batteries exceeding a watt-hour rating of 100 Wh but not exceeding 160 Wh may be carried as spare batteries in carry-on baggage, or in equipment in either checked or carry-on baggage. Are permitted in aircraft as carry-on baggage only with the approval of the operator(s).</p>
			<p>Batteries must be of a type that meets the requirements of the UN manual of Tests and Criteria Part III, subsection 38.3.</p>
			<p>No more than two individually protected spare batteries per person may be carried</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>labelling</act>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Training requirements</strong></h3>	
			<p>Personnel shall be trained in the contents of dangerous goods provisions commensurate with their duties and responsibilities, before assuming responsibilities.</p>
			<p>Road and maritime regulations allow employees, for which required training has not yet been provided, to perform functions under the direct supervision of a trained person</p>.
			<p>Where the carriage of dangerous goods involves a multimodal transport operation, the personnel shall be aware of the requirements concerning other transport modes.</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-table2.jpg"/></p>
			<p><i>(*) For small excepted batteries, IATA require that any person preparing or offering cells or batteries for transport must receive adequate instructions on these requirements commensurate with their responsibilities.</i></p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Vehicle</prodType>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Lithium batteries in vehicles</strong></h3>	
			<p><b>UN3171 Battery-powered vehicles:</b> This entry only applies to vehicles powered by lithium ion batteries which are transported with these batteries installed. For the purpose of this special provision, vehicles are self-propelled apparatus designed to carry one of more persons or goods. Examples of such vehicles are electrically-powered cars, scooters, three and four-wheeled vehicles or motorcycles, battery-assisted bicycles (e bikes), wheelchairs, lawn tractors, boats and aircraft. Examples of equipment are lawnmowers, cleaning machine, model boats and model aircraft.</p>
			<p><b>IATA:</b> Fully regulated, class 9 (UN 3171) – PI 952 – battery-powered vehicles must meet the following requirements:</p>
			<ul><li>Lithium batteries installed in a vehicle must be of a type that has successfully passed the tests specified in the UN Manual of Tests and Criteria, Part III, subsection 38.3, unless otherwise approved by the appropriate national authority of the State of origin</li>
			<li>All batteries must be installed and securely fastened in the battery holder of the vehicle, machinery or equipment and be protected in such a manner as to prevent damage and short circuits.</li></ul>
			<p>TVehicles equipped with theft-protection devices, installed radio communications equipment or navigational system must have such devices, equipment or systems disabled. No quantity limits per packaged in passenger and cargo aircraft.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>