<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Transportation</proc>	
<title>Storage before transportation</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Pack | Module | Damaged cell | Damaged pack | Damaged module</prodType>
		<act>storing</act>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEEE 1625</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>6.13</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>6.13.2</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<reqs> <!-- place to list the requirements, put on the side of the window -->
			<refReq_tag>IEC 62281</refReq_tag>
			<refReq_part>n.a.</refReq_part>
			<refReq_chNo>7</refReq_chNo>
			<refReq_clNo>7.4</refReq_clNo>
		</reqs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p> ADD RECOMMENDATIONS </p>
			<p>When the batteries (cell, module or pack) are stored, the following safety aspects need to be taken into consideration</p>
			<ul><li>To avoid deterioration of the performance and/or surface corrosion due to high temperature or humidity, the batteries need to be stored in well ventilated, dry and cool conditions.</li> 
			<li>The battery cartons may not be stacked higher than specified by the manufacturer. The batteries in the lowest carton may be deformed and leakage may occur due to the weight.</li>
			<li>Don’t store or display batteries in direct sun or places where they get exposed to rain. The storage should be a controlled environment.</li>
			<li>Use only original packages for the battery storage. When batteries are unpacked and mixed they may be short-circuited or damaged.</li>
			<li>To detect an early temperature increase in a battery (which can lead to a thermal runaway) the temperature of a stored components need to be checked regularly</li>
			<li>When damaged components are stored, extra awareness and monitoring is needed. In these cases the probability on a thermal runaway, increases.</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>