<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Transportation</proc>	
<title>Transportation by road from plant to other plant</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Damaged cell | Module | Damaged module | Pack | Damaged pack</prodType>
		<inputs>ADR</inputs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>The transportation process by road containes loading of a lorry, the actual travel from plant to plant
			and the unloading of the lorry. Note that when selecting a transport company care should be taken that 
			the company can transport the components according to the ADR-regulations. The ADR gives next to labelling
			and packaging requirements, also requirements concerning loading of a lorry with dangerous goods and concerning
			training and qualification of the personel handling the goods.</p>
			
			<p>The transportation documents, made during the preparation of the transport, shall be given to the transporter.</p>
		
			<p>During transportation thermal runway is the main risk, especially for scrap, used and damaged components. 
			If a thermal runaway starts and propagate the consequences and severity of damages to infrastructure and persons can be very high. 
			It is therefore recommended to check the temperature on a regulare base during transport. These timely watch depends on the type
			of transported components and the transport duration. It is also recommended to use ventilated containers to avoid a temperature 
			increase during transport.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Damaged cell</prodType>
		<recoms>recomm_6</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_10</recoms>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module | Damaged module</prodType>
		<recoms>recomm_35</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_10</recoms>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack | Damaged pack</prodType>
		<recoms>recomm_107</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_10</recoms>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>