<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Transportation</proc>	
<title>Transportation on ship</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Damaged cell | Module | Damaged module | Pack | Damaged pack</prodType>
		<inputs>ADR</inputs>
		<inputs>IMDG</inputs>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>This transportation contains the following steps:</p>
			<ul><li>Transporting the components over road to the harbour.</li>
			<li>Possible storage of the components at the harbour</li>
			<li>Transporting the components by ship to destination harbour</li>
			<li>It is possible that the components are stored in the destination harbour</li>
			<li>Transporting the component to the final destination by land transport</li></ul>

			<p>For the land transport from the sender to the harbour and the harbour to the receiver, 
			the ADR is applicable. This implies that the transporter need to comply with the ADR regulation 
			and that an ADR transport document shall be available.</p>

			<p> For the sea transport the MDGF (Multimodal Dangerous Goods Form) document shall be handed to the 
			shipping company. Extra information about emergency response, what to do when accidents and incidents occur need to be given.</p>

			<p>When the components are placed into storage in the harbour, appropriate action shall be 
			taken to avoid sever incidents due to thermal reactions in the components.</p>

			<p>During transportation thermal runway is the main risk, especially for scrap, used and damaged components. 
			If a thermal runaway starts and propagate the consequences and severity of damages to infrastructure and persons can be very high. 
			It is therefore recommended to check the temperature on a regulare base during transport. These timely watch depends on the type
			of transported components and the transport duration. It is also recommended to use ventilated containers to avoid a temperature 
			increase during transport.</p>

			<p>TEMPLATE: ADR en MDGF doc</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Damaged cell</prodType>
		<recoms>recomm_6</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_10</recoms>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module | Damaged module</prodType>
		<recoms>recomm_35</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_10</recoms>	
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack | Damaged pack</prodType>
		<recoms>recomm_107</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_10</recoms>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>