<step>
<proc>Transportation</proc>	
<title>Transporting batteries in equipment by land</title>
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell</prodType>
		<act>packing | labelling</act>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Cells transported in equipment</strong></h3>
			<p><strong>LITHIUM ION CELLS CONTAINED IN EQUIPMENT  - Fully regulated cells</strong></p>
			<p>Applies to: Lithium ion cells contained in equipment with a Watt-hour rating in excess of  20 Wh/cell</p>
			<p>Un No., Proper shipping name: UN 3481, LITHIUM ION BATTERIES CONTAINED IN EQUIPMENT</p>
			<p>Class: 9</p>
			<p>Packing group: II</p>
			<p>Hazard Label:</p>
			<ul><li>Labels must be in the form of a square set at an angle of 50° (diamond-shaped) with minimum dimensions of 100 mm by 100 mm.</li>
			<li>They must have a line 5 mm inside the edge and running parallel with it.</li></ul>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure2.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Prerequisite: Cells must meet the General Requirements of flow Transportation in particular the test requirements.</p>
			<p>Specific Requirements:</p>
			<ul><li>Each cell incorporates a safety venting device or is designed to preclude a violent rupture under normal conditions of carriage.</li>
			<li>Each cell is equipped with an effective means of preventing external short circuits.</li>
			<li>Equipment must be equipped with an effective means of preventing accidental activation.</li></ul>
			<p>Transport mode: ADR P903</p>
			<p>Packaging instructions: Cells must be protected against short circuit, including protection against contact with conductive materials within the same packaging that could lead to a short circuit. Equipment containing cells must be packed	in strong outer packagings. The equipment containing the cells must be secured against movement within	the outer packaging and be packed so as to prevent accidental operation during transport;</p>
			<p>Packaging: Packaging tests not necessary</p>
			<p>Weight limit lithium batteries per piece of equipment: No limit</p>
			<p>Tunnel code: (E)</p>
			<p>Transport cat.: 2</p>
			<p>Exemptions: chapter 1.1.3.6 – limit ≤333 kg Net</p>
			<p>Marking and Handling Labels on Packages: UN 3481</p>
			<p>Overpack: “Overpack”</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure2.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Documents: Transport document</p>
			<p>Practical example of packaging, marking and labelling of packages containing lithium ion cells fully regulated installed in equipment: Li-ion Wh rating 30 Wh/cell – Net weight 15 kg</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure16.jpg"/></p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure17.jpg"/></p>
		
			<p><strong>LITHIUM ION CELLS CONTAINED IN EQUIPMENT – Small cells exempted</strong></p>
			<p>Applies to: Lithium ion cells contained in equipment with a Watt-hour rating not exceeding 20 Wh/cell</p>
			<p>Un No., Proper shipping name: UN 3480, LITHIUM ION BATTERIES CONTAINED IN EQUIPMENT</p>
			<p>Class: 9</p>
			<p>Packing group: II</p>
			<p>Hazard Label:  Not required</p>
			<p>Prerequisite: Cells must meet the General Requirements of flow Transportation in particular the test requirements.</p>
			<p>Exemption conditions: SP 188</p>
			<ul><li>Cells when installed in equipment must be protected from damage and short circuit, must be secured against movement within the outer packaging.</li>
			<li>The equipment must be equipped with an effective means of preventing accidental activation.</li>
			<li>Devices such as radio frequent identification (RFID) tags, watches and temperature loggers, which are not capable of generating a dangerous evolution of heat, may be transported when intentionally active.</li></ul>
			<p>Packaging: The equipment must be packed in strong outer packagings constructed of suitable material of adequate	 strength	 and  design  in  relation  to  the  packaging's  capacity  and  its  intended use unless the  cell is afforded equivalent protection by the equipment in which it is contained.</p>
			<p>Weight limit batteries/package: No limit</p>
			<p>Marking and Handling Labels on Packages:</p>
			<ul><li>an indication that the package contains "lithium ion cells”</li>
			<li>an indication that the package shall be handled with care and that	a flammability hazard exists if the package is damaged;</li>
			<li>an indication	that special procedures shall be followed in the event the package is damaged,  to include. Inspection and repacking if necessary;</li>
			<li>a telephone number for additional information;</li></ul>
			<p>Marking	is not required for packages containing:</p>
			<ul><li>Button cell installed in equipment (including circuit boards),</li>
			<li>≤ 4 cells installed in equipment</li></ul>
			<p>Overpack: “Overpack”</p>
			<p>Documents: Transport document is not required</p>
			<p>Each consignment must be accompanied with a document with an indication that:</p>
			<ul><li>The package contains lithium ion	cells;</li>		
			<li>The package must be handled with care and that a flammability hazard exists	if the package is damaged;</li>
			<li>Special	 procedures must be followed in the event the package is damaged, to include inspection and repacking if necessary; and</li>
			<li>A telephone number for additional information.</li></ul>	
			<p>Instruction to personnel: Any person preparing or offering cells for transport must receive adequate instruction on these requirements commensurate with their responsibilities.</p>
			<p>Practical example of packaging, marking and labelling of packages containing small exempted lithium ion cells installed in equipment: Li-ion Wh rating 5 Wh/cell – Net weight 3 kg.</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure18.jpg"/></p>
		
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing | labelling</act>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Modules and Packs transported in equipment</strong></h3>
			<p><strong>LITHIUM ION BATTERIES CONTAINED IN EQUIPMENT – Fully regulated batteries</strong></p>
			<p>Applies to: Lithium ion batteries contained in equipment with a Watt-hour rating in excess of 100 Wh/battery</p>
			<p>Un No., Proper shipping name: UN 3481, LITHIUM ION BATTERIES CONTAINED IN EQUIPMENT</p>
			<p>Class: 9</p>
			<p>Packing group: II</p>
			<p>Hazard Label:</p>
			<ul><li>Labels must be in the form of a square set at an angle of 50° (diamond-shaped) with minimum dimensions of 100 mm by 100 mm.</li>
			<li>They must have a line 5 mm inside the edge and running parallel with it.</li></ul>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure2.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Prerequisite: Batteries must meet the General Requirements of flow Transportation in particular the test requirements.</p>
			<p>Specific Requirements:</p>
			<ul><li>Each battery incorporates a safety venting device or is designed to preclude a violent rupture under normal conditions of carriage.</li>
			<li>Each battery is equipped with an effective means of preventing external short circuits.</li>
			<li>Equipment must be equipped with an effective means of preventing accidental activation.</li>
			<li>Each battery containing cells or series of cells connected in parallel must be equipped with an effective means as necessary, to prevent dangerous reverse current flow (e.g. diodes, fuses).</li>
			<li>Batteries manufactured after 31 December 2011 must be marked with the Wh rating in the outside case</li></ul>
			<p>Transport mode: ADR P903</p>
			<p>Packaging instructions: Batteries must be protected against short circuit, including protection against contact with conductive materials within the same packaging that could lead to a short circuit. Equipment containing batteries must be packed	in strong outer packagings. The equipment containing the batteries must be secured against movement within the outer packaging and be packed so as to prevent accidental operation during transport;</p>
			<p>Packaging: Packaging tests not necessary</p>
			<p>Weight limit lithium batteries per piece of equipment: No limit</p>
			<p>Tunnel code: (E)</p>
			<p>Transport cat.: 2</p>
			<p>Exemptions: chapter 1.1.3.6 – limit ≤333 kg Net</p>
			<p>Marking and Handling Labels on Packages: UN 3481</p>
			<p>Overpack: “Overpack”</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure2.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Documents: Transport document</p>
			<p>Practical example of packaging, marking and labelling of packages containing lithium ion cells fully regulated installed in equipment: Li-ion Wh rating 120 Wh/cell – Net weight 15 kg</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure26.jpg"/></p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure77.jpg"/></p>

			<p><strong>LITHIUM ION BATTERIES PACKED WITH EQUIPMENT – Fully regulated batteries</strong></p>
			<p>Applies to: Lithium ion batteries contained in equipment with a Watt-hour rating not exceeding 100 Wh/battery</p>
			<p>Un No., Proper shipping name: UN 3481, LITHIUM ION BATTERIES CONTAINED IN EQUIPMENT</p>
			<p>Class: 9</p>
			<p>Packing group: II</p>
			<p>Hazard Label:  Not required</p>
			<p>Prerequisite: Batteries must meet the General Requirements of flow Transportation in particular the test requirements.</p>
			<p>Specific Requirements:</p>
			<ul><li>The Watt-hour rating must be marked on the outside of the battery case except those manufactured before 1 January 2009</li></ul>
			<p>Transport mode: ADR</p>
			<p>Exempt conditions: SP 188</p>
			<ul><li>Batteries when installed in equipment must be protected from damage and short circuit, must be secured against movement within the outer packaging.</li>
			<li>The equipment must be equipped with an effective means of preventing accidental activation.</li>
			<li>Devices such as radio frequent identification (RFID) tags, watches and temperature loggers, which are not capable of generating a dangerous evolution of heat, may be transported when intentionally active.</li></ul>
			<p>Packaging: The equipment must be packed in strong outer packagings constructed of suitable material of adequate	 strength	 and  design  in  relation  to  the  packaging's  capacity  and  its  intended use unless the  cell is afforded equivalent protection by the equipment in which it is contained.</p>
			<p>Weight limit: 30 kg Gross</p>
			<p>Marking and Handling Labels on Packages:</p>
			<ul><li>an indication that the package contains "lithium ion batteries”</li>
			<li>an indication that the package shall be handled with care and that	a flammability hazard exists if the package is damaged;</li>
			<li>an indication	that special procedures shall be followed in the event the package is damaged, to include Inspection and repacking if necessary;</li>
			<li>a telephone number for additional information;</li></ul>
			<p>Marking is not required for packages containing:</p>
			<ul><li>Button cell installed in equipment (including circuit boards),</li>
			<li>≤ 2 batteries installed in equipment</li></ul>
			<p>Overpack: “Overpack”</p>
			<p>Documents: Transport document is not required</p>
			<p>Each consignment must be accompanied with a document with an indication that:</p>
			<ul><li>The package contains lithium ion cells;</li>
			<li>The package must be handled with care and that a flammability hazard exists	if the package is damaged;</li>
			<li>Special	 procedures must be followed in the event the package is damaged, to include inspection and repacking if necessary; and</li>
			<li>A telephone number for additional information.</li></ul>
			<p>Instructions to personnel: Any person preparing or offering batteries for transport must receive adequate instructions on these requirements commensurate with their responsibilities.</p>
			<p>Practical example of packaging, marking and labelling of packages containing lithium ion batteries partially exempted: Li-ion Wh rating 40 Wh/cell – N. Batteries/package > 2 – Gross weight 8 kg</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure28.jpg"/></p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
</step>