<step>
<proc>Transportation</proc>	
<title>Transporting waste by sea</title>
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell | Module | Pack</prodType>
		<act>packing | labelling</act>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Waste transported by sea</strong></h3>
			<p><strong>WASTE LITHIUM ION CELLS & BATTERIES – Fully regulated P903 ADR & IMDG</strong></p>
			<p>Applies to:</p>
			<ul><li>Waste Lithium ion cells with a Watt-hour rating in excess of 20 Wh/cell</li>
			<li>Waste Lithium ion  batteries with a Watt-hour rating in excess of 100Wh/battery</li></ul>
			<p>Note: waste cells and batteries transported as new one.</p>
			<p>Un No., Proper shipping name: UN 3480, LITHIUM ION BATTERIES</p>
			<p>Class: 9</p>
			<p>Packing group: II</p>
			<p>Label:</p> 
			<ul><li>Labels must be in the form of a square set at an angle of 50° (diamond-shaped) with minimum dimensions of 100 mm by 100 mm; except in the case of packages od such dimensions that they can only bear smaller labels.</li>
			<li>They must have a line 5 mm inside the edge and running parallel with it.</li></ul>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure2.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Prerequisite: Cells must meet the General Requirements of flow Transportation.</p>
			<ul><li>Each battery incorporates a safety venting device or is designed to preclude a violent rupture under normal conditions of carriage.</li>
			<li>Each battery is equipped with an effective means of preventing external short circuits.</li>
			<li>Each battery containing cells or series of cells connected in parallel must be equipped with an effective means, as necessary, to prevent dangerous reverse current flow (e.g. diodes, fuses).</li>
			<li>Batteries manufactured after 31 December 2011 must be marked with the Wh rating on the outside case.</li></ul>
			<p>Transport mode: IMDG</p>
			<p>Packing instructions: P903</p>
			<ul><li>Cells must be protected against short circuit, including protection against contact with conductive materials within the same packaging which could cause a short circuit.</li>
			<li>Cells must be packed so that they are protected against damage caused by the movement or placement of the cells within the packaging.</li>
			<li>Use only approved packaging conforming to PG II performance level.</li></ul>
			<p>Packagings:</p>
			<ul><li>Drums (1A2, 1B2, 1N2, 1H2, 1D, 1G)</li>
			<li>Boxes (4A, 4B, 4N, 4C1, 4C2, 4D, 4F, 4G, 4H1, 4H2)</li>
			<li>Jerricans (3A2, 3B2, 3H2)</li></ul>
			<p>Batteries ≥ 12 h (gross) with a  strong impact resistant outer casing:</p>
			<p>Not required UN approved packagings for batteries, or assemblies of such batteries, when packed in strong outer packagings or protective enclosures (i.g. fully enclosed or wooden slatted crates)</p>
			<p>Allowed transport on Pallets or otter handling devices</p>
			<p>Batteries must be secured to prevent inadvertent movement, and the terminals must not support the weight of other superimposed elements</p>
			<p>Weight limit: No limit</p>
			<p>Tunnel code: -</p>
			<p>Transport cat.: -</p>
			<p>Exemptions: -</p>
			<p>Marking: UN 3480 LITHIUM ION BATTERIES</p>
			<p>Overpack: “Overpack”</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure2.jpg"/></p>
			<p>Documents: MDGF</p>
			<p>Practical example of packaging, marking and labelling of packages containing waste lithium ion cells and batteries, fully regulated, according Packing Isntrcution P903 (ADR & IMDG).</p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure48.jpg"/></p>
			<p><img alt="" src="http://193.104.8.63/bundles/cegekaflandersdrive/images/standards/15 Transport/Transport-figure50.jpg"/></p>
		]]></htmltext>
		</paragraph>	
</description>
</step>