<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Internal logistics</proc>	
<title>Internal logistics to storage area</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Cell  | Damaged cell</prodType>
		<act>moving | lifting | placing</act>		
		<recoms>recomm_110</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_111</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the cells are correctly packed, they can be moved to the storage area. During the activities the normal prevention measures of internal logistics need to be taken into account. These are for example:</p>
			<ul><li>Only skilled person can drive with a fork lift</li>
			<li>The limits of the fork lift may not be exceeded</li>
			<li>There shall be internal transportation rules (example ‘Intern verkeersplan’ <b>Add TEMPLATE</b>)</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Module | Damaged module</prodType>
		<act>moving | lifting | placing</act>		
		<recoms>recomm_33</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_58</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_110</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_111</recoms>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the modules are correctly packed, they can be moved to the storage area. During the activities the normal prevention measures of internal logistics need to be taken into account to avoid mechanical abuse which can lead to temperature increase and gas formation or leakage. These are for example:</p>
			<ul><li>Only skilled person can drive with a fork lift</li>
			<li>The limits of the fork lift may not be exceeded</li>
			<li>There shall be internal transportation rules (example ‘Intern verkeersplan’<b>Add TEMPLATE</b>)</li></ul>
			<p>The operator need to be aware of the probability that external short circuit can exists when modules are moved. To detect thermal runaway in an early stage, it is also recommended to monitor the temperature.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Pack | Damaged pack</prodType>
		<act>moving | lifting | placing</act>	
		<recoms>recomm_77</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_110</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_111</recoms>			
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When the packs are correctly packed, they can be moved to the storage area. During the activities the normal prevention measures of internal logistics need to be taken into account to avoid mechanical abuse which can lead to temperature increase and gas formation or leakage. These are for example:</p>
			<ul><li>Only skilled person can drive with a fork lift</li>
			<li>The limits of the fork lift may not be exceeded</li>
			<li>There shall be internal transportation rules (example ‘Intern verkeersplan’<b>Add TEMPLATE</b>)</li></ul>
			<p>To detect thermal runaway in an early stage, it is also recommended to monitor the temperature.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged pack</prodType>
		<act>moving | lifting | placing</act>	
		<recoms>recomm_96</recoms>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Damaged packs have higher chance to go into thermal runaway. During the logistics the temperature need to be checked regular.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>