<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Handling damaged components</proc>	
<title>Handling damaged components</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph><!-- general -->
		<prodType>Damaged cell | Damaged module | Damaged pack | Pack | Cell | Module</prodType>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<h3><strong>Purpose and scope</strong></h3>
			<p>During the complete life cycle of the battery, damaged components need to be handled in a safe way. A damaged 
				component has a macroscopic damage and cannot be used anymore. These damaged components need to be stored, transported, 
				disassembled and recycled in a safe way.</p>
			<p>Note: It can be that a module or pack is damaged in such a way that it can be repairable or that parts can be reused for other modules or packs.</p>	
			<p>Note: In the defined lifecycle the decision 'Damaged component?' before and after assembling. it should be taken into account that damaged components may
			occur during all other processes. In these cases this flow can also be followed.</p> 
			<h3><strong>Structure of the process</strong></h3>
		]]></htmltext>	
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph><!-- damaged pack specific -->
		<prodType>Damaged pack | Pack </prodType>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Starting from a damaged pack: the damaged pack need to be transported to the pack<i>producer/pack disassemble plant</i>. 
				There the damaged pack is disassembled and parts which can be reused are separated from the damaged parts.</p>
		]]></htmltext>	
	</paragraph>			
	<paragraph><!-- damaged module specific -->
		<prodType>Damaged module | Module</prodType>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Damaged modules can occur in the production line but also after the disassembling of a damaged pack. 
				The modules need to be transported to the<i>module producer/modules disassemble plant</i>. There the damaged modules 
				are disassembled and parts which can be reused are separated from the damaged parts</p>
		]]></htmltext>	
	</paragraph>		
	<paragraph><!-- damaged cell specific -->
		<prodType>Damaged cell | Cell</prodType>		
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>Damaged cells can occur in the production line but also after the disassembling of a damaged module. 
				The cells need to be transported to a plant where they can be recycled.</p>
		]]></htmltext>	
	</paragraph>		
</description>	
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>