<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<step>
<proc>Handling damaged components</proc>	
<title>Disassembling damaged modules</title>	
<description>	
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged module | Module</prodType>
		<act>lifting | moving | placing</act>							
		<recoms>recomm_57</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_60</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_61</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_46</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_47</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_51</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_54</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>When a damaged module cannot be repaired, it need to be recycled. Precautions need to be taken when the damaged module is moved, lifted and placed in the repair area. The following recommendations are valid for the package:</p>
			<ul><li>Appropriate package for the damaged module to avoid external short circuit</li>
			<li>Individual damaged modules shall be separated by moulded trays to avoid thermal runaway propagation</li>
			<li>The enclosure shall be resistant against mechanical abuse which could lead to gas formation</li>
			<li>To avoid injuries due to rupture of a module the enclosure needs to be resistant against internal pressure.</li></ul>
			<p>To further decrease the risk and the severity of injuries caused by external short circuit, one current connector needs to be covered and the operator needs to wear safety glasses and gloves.</p>
			<p>During these activities the temperature shall be monitored to detect the start of a thermal runaway.</p>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
	<paragraph>
		<prodType>Damaged module | Module</prodType>
		<act>module disassembling</act>							
		<recoms>recomm_51</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_54</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_48</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_62</recoms>
		<recoms>recomm_63</recoms>
		<htmltext><![CDATA[
			<p>During this disassembling the appropriate measures to avoid external short circuit and thermal runaway need to be taken:</p>
			<ul><li>Use of correct insulated tooling and covering the current collector</li>
			<li>Use of personal protection measures</li>
			<li>Checking the temperature and placing the modules in moulded trays to avoid thermal runaway and its propagation.</li></ul>
		]]></htmltext>
	</paragraph>
</description>
<processOwner>company0</processOwner>
</step>